Welcome back. So, in this video,
欢迎回来 在这一段视频中
I'm going to be showing you how to save and load models that you've trained with PyTorch.
我将演示如何保存和加载已通过 PyTorch 训练的模型
Again, this is important because most of the time you'll want
再次声明 这一点非常重要 因为在大多数情况下
to train your network on some data and then just save it to disk,
需要用某些数据对网络进行训练 将其保存到磁盘
and then you can later load it up and train more
以后可以加载 继续训练
or use it for inference, like making predictions.
或用它进行推断 例如 预测
So I've already gone ahead and ran most of this codes,
我已经运行了大部分代码
trained my network on fashion hymnist.
用 fashion hymnist 训练了网络
Again, we see we get about an accuracy of 84-85 percent.
可以看出 准确度大约是 84 - 85%
Now that the network is trained,
现在已经训练了网络
we actually don't want to take these weights,
我们不想使用这些权重
never really learned this problem,
以前从没学习过这个问题
and we want to save them so that we can in the future load them back up and use it again.
想将其保存下来 以后可以重新加载 再次使用
These weights, these parameters,
这些权重 这些参数
are actually stored in model.state_dict.
实际都存储在 model.state_dict 中
So we print this out, so we can see our network here.
将其打印出来 现在可以看见网络
So we have two hidden layers.
有两个隐藏层
So, this one goes to 500, 500 to 100,
这个输出是 500 这个输入是 500 输出是 100
and then this goes to our output layer of 10 output units,
这个输出层有 10 个输出单元
and then we have drop out.
还使用了丢弃法
So this is what our network looks like.
网络就是这样
If we look at the state_dict keys,
state_dict 键
this is showing us we have hidden layers at zero weight. So that's here.
显示隐藏层的权重为零 就是这里
Hidden layers gives us a bias,
隐藏层有偏差
the second hidden layer gives us the weight
第二个隐藏层有权重
and also the weights and bias for our output layer.
输出层也有权重和偏差
So that the tensors that for our weights and
权重和偏差张量
biases are actually stored and model.state_dict.
实际存储在 model.state_dict 中
So this is what typically you want to save.
这就是一般情况下需要保存的内容
So to save the state_dict, it's pretty simple.
state_dict 的保存非常简单
So use the torch.save,
使用 torch.save
and then pass in your model.state_dict and then call it checkpoint.pth.
然后传入 model.state_dict 命名为 checkpoint.pth
There you go. It's saved.
好了 已经保存了
So once it's saved, we can then load in the state_dict.
保存之后 就可以在 state_dict 中加载
So state_dict is equal to torch.load.
state_dict = torch.load
Let's give it the same thing, checkpoint.pth,
将 state_dict 同样命名为
and then one p to state_dict,
checkpoint.pth
then we can print this out just see.keys.
然后可以打印 .keys
So it gives us the same layers that we saw up here, so in layers.0.weight.
这样得出的层和我们在 layers.0.weight 中看到的相同
So, we all see the same thing.
都是一样的
But the state_dict, it's self loaded.
但是 state_dict 是自动加载的
How do we actually load this into a model?
怎么将其加载到模型中？
So we say model.load_state_dict and we pass in our state_dict.
例如 model.load_state_dict 传入 state_dict
So notice that we need to have our model existing already.
请注意 模型应该已经存在
We need to have it already created,
应该已经创建
and it's going to be created with randomly initialize the weights and biases.
创建时 权重和偏差是随机初始化的
The parameters are going to be randomly initialized.
参数是随机初始化的
Basically we just pass in our state dict and then
刚才传入了 state_dict
those random parameters are replaced by the ones that we trained previously.
然后用我们之前训练过的参数替代这些随机参数
This seems pretty straightforward,
看起来很简单
you just save your state_dict and you can load it backup into a model,
保存 state_dict 可以将其重新加载到模型中
but it's not actually all that simple,
但在实际情况中 不是一直这么简单
and I'll show you why.
我现在给你演示原因
So, if I create a new network,
如果创建了一个新网络
784 at normal, 10 output units,
输入一般是 784 有 10 个输出单元
but this time I'm going to use three hidden layers with 400,
但是现在我将使用三个隐藏层
200 and 100 units each.
分别有 400 200 和 100 个单元
Okay. So now, I have this pre-trained State_dict, right?
好了 现在这个 state_dict 已经进行了预训练 对吧？
So it's like, okay well I created this new model,
已经创建了新模型
I'm going to try to load this state_dict, and it gives me an error.
我将尝试加载这个 state_dict 但它提示错误
So basically it says,
意思是说
inconsistent tensor size, expected tensor,
张量大小不一致 预期张量的大小
this size but the sources is dense.
是这样 但来源元素较多
Right? So basically what that means is that when I
对吧？ 意思就是
trained this state_dict with this checkpoint,
用这个检查点训练这个 state_dict 时
I had a different network architecture.
使用的网络架构不同
So that in the original network I had 500 units in the first layer,
在原始网络中 第一层有 500 个单元
and now I have 400 units in the first layer.
现在第一层有 400 个单元
So, the thing is that when you build your network and you train it,
问题就是 建立和训练网络
when you load the state_dict back up,
以及重新加载 state_dict 时
it has to go to a model with exactly the same architecture.
模型的架构必须完全相同
So if you have code that can generate networks with
如果在重新加载 state_dict 时
different architectures when you load your your state_dict back up,
代码可以生成具有不同架构的网络
you also have to include information about the architecture.
那么必须添加架构的信息
So, for instance, here with this network since I have
例如 在这个网络中 由于
an arbitrary number of hidden layers,
隐藏层的数量是随机的
I need to include this information about the hidden layers in my checkpoint that I saved.
需要在保存的检查点中添加隐藏层的信息
To rebuild this model exactly as it was trained,
要将模型重建成之前训练的架构
I'm going to store the state_dict and all the information about the model architecture.
需要保存 state_dict 和模型架构的所有信息
Here I can say let's say, create a dictionary,
可以创建一个字典
given it my input size it's 784,
将输入大小设为 784
my output size 10.
输出大小设为 10
So if I have a model,
如果有一个模型
then I can do up features for each model.
可以运行 each.out_features for each in model.hidden_layers
So remember here that model.hidden_layers is a list of these linear operations.
请记住 model.hidden_layers 是这些线性运算的列表
So basically hidden_layers is a list of the layers in the network.
hidden_layers 是网络中层的列表
So, to get the actual values
为了获得实际值
I had set for the hidden_layers depending on the number of units,
我已经根据单元数量设置了 hidden_layers
I just call out features on each of those layers.
在每个层上调用 out_features
So this is basically just going through each of the layers,
就是遍历这个隐藏层列表中的每个层
in this list of hidden layers and then getting
然后获取这个层中的
the number of features or units in that layer.
特征或单元数量
Then I can save the state_dict.
然后可以保存 state_dict
Then once I have that dictionary,
创建字典之后
then I can simply save the dictionary.
可以保存字典
Checkpoint, checkpoint.pth again. There you go.
checkpoint, ‘checkpoint.pth’ 好了
Now our checkpoint has all the necessary information we need to rebuild our model.
现在 检查点包含了重建模型所需的所有必要信息
So what I'd like to do is create
我想创建
a function just called like load_checkpoint and give it a file path,
一个函数 叫做 load_checkpoint 给它指定一个文件路径
and then we can load our checkpoint.
然后可以加载检查点
So our checkpoint is torch.load(file path) then we can create our model.
检查点是 torch.load(filepath) 然后就可以创建模型了
So our model is network,
我们的模型是网络
then we get our parameters for this model from our checkpoint.
从检查点获取这个模型的参数
So we can put in the input size,
可以传入输入大小
we can put in the output size,
传入输出大小
we pass in the hidden layers.
传入隐藏层
So what this does is passing in
这样就传入了
all the necessary arguments parameters to create our model.
创建模型所需的所有必要参数
So, once we have our model,
获得模型之后
then we can load the state_dict from uh,
就可以加载 state_dict
I want to return the model.
现在返回模型
Then we can call the checkpoint, passed in checkpoint.pth.
然后可以调用检查点 传入 checkpoint.pth
So then we load the model and we successfully load
我们加载了模型 并成功加载了
the state_dict and everything is present.
state_dict 所有元素齐全
So in general that's how you're going to save and load your networks.
这基本就是保存和加载网络的步骤
So, it's important to remember that every
还要记住
parameter that you use for building your network,
用于建立网络的每个参数
you have to also include that in your checkpoints.
都必须包含在检查点中
So you can reconstruct your model exactly the same way it was when you saved it.
这样 重建的模型和之前保存的会完全相同
Right. See you in the next video. Cheers
好了 下一段视频见 谢谢